A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Homes, Series I FA318
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Seal Harbor, ME
  - Seal Harbor - Churches - Mount Desert Larger Parish - Malcolm B. Dana, 1927-1933 (Box 65, Folder 660)
    Son of Malcolm Dana, considered for post at Larger Parish. Worked at Bar Harbor Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA).
  - Seal Harbor - Churches - Mount Desert Larger Parish - Frank S. Staley's Report, 1931 (Box 65, Folder 661)
    Staley investigated financial procedures of parish, made recommendations.
  - Seal Harbor - Churches - Mount Desert Larger Parish - Arthur Wilson, 1927-1932 (Box 65, Folder 662)
    Minister for five years of Larger Parish. Rockefeller assistance.
  - Seal Harbor - Churches - Mount Desert Larger Parish, 1934-1943 (Box 65, Folder 663)
  - Seal Harbor - Churches - Mount Desert Larger Parish, 1944-1948 (Box 66, Folder 664)
  - Seal Harbor - Churches - Mount Desert Larger Parish, 1941-1951 (Box 66, Folder 665)
  - Seal Harbor - Churches - Mount Desert Larger Parish, 1951-1961 (Box 66, Folder 666)
  - Seal Harbor - Churches - Mount Desert Larger Parish - 25th Anniversary, 1949-1950 (Box 66, Folder 667)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s contribution, wrote preface for booklet.
  - Seal Harbor - Churches - Mount Desert Larger Parish - McGee Resignation, 1947 (Box 66, Folder 668)
    Minister resigned to have his own church. Led to John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s thoughtful consideration of goals of Larger Parish.
  - Seal Harbor - Churches - Mount Desert Larger Parish - Parsonage Changes, 1945-1947 (Box 66, Folder 669)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributes $8,000 for renovations.
  - Seal Harbor - Churches - Mount Desert Larger Parish - Somesville Parsonage, 1944-1945 (Box 66, Folder 670)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contribution toward parsonage.
  - Seal Harbor - Churches - Mount Desert Larger Parish - Southwest Harbor-Tremont Larger Parish, 1932-1944 (Box 66, Folder 671)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. special contribution, later declinations.
  - Seal Harbor - Churches - Mount Desert Large Parish - Contributions, 1926-1948 (Box 67, Folder 672)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s interest in support of cooperative Christian churches - 1927 - $1,500, 1928-1947 - $2,500, 1948-1950 - $3,000, 1951 - $3,500. Other gifts to reserve fund, etc. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Charles K. Savage, Robert W. Gumbel, Phillip Keebler.
  - Seal Harbor - Churches - Mount Desert Large Parish - Contributions, 1949-1960 (Box 67, Folder 673)
  - Seal Harbor - Churches - Mount Desert Large Parish - Rockefeller Brothers Fund Contributions, 1931-1948 (Box 67, Folder 674)
    Personal contributions by John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Nelson A. Rockefeller. Rockefeller Brothers Fund assumed contributions in 1941. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. solicited earlier gifts from his sons for Parish. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Nelson A. Rockefeller.
  - Seal Harbor - Churches - Mount Desert Large Parish - David Rockefeller, 1960-1961 (Box 67, Folder 675)
    Memorial service for John D. Rockefeller, Jr. 1961 Annual Meeting for Mt. Desert Larger Parish, Dr. Malik speaker. Correspondents include David Rockefeller, Dana S. Creel, Hollis M. Smith, Henry C. Lodge, Jr., Dr. Charles Malik, Richard Dana.
  - Seal Harbor - Churches - Mount Desert Large Parish - L. M. Hodges Article, 1942-1944 (Box 67, Folder 676)
    Description of genesis, climate and work of Larger Parish. Written with John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s assistance. Published by the Parish at John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s expense. Extra copies.
  - Seal Harbor - Churches - Mount Desert Large Parish - L. M. Hodges Article, 1942 (Box 67, Folder 677)
  - Seal Harbor - Churches - Mount Desert Large Parish - Printed Materials, 1925-1949 (Box 67, Folder 678)
    1930 appreciation of Larger Parish, constitution and by-laws. Ten year summary, 1932 Historical Manual.
  - Seal Harbor - Churches - Mount Desert Large Parish - Eunice B. Shaw, 1939-1947 (Box 67, Folder 679)
    Educator and Minister in Larger Parish. Friendship with John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Gifts to her. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Eunice B. Shaw.
  - Seal Harbor - Churches - Otter Creek Church and Community House, 1924-1961 (Box 67, Folder 680)
    Annual gifts to church fair. Special gift for organ. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Martha Baird Rockefeller.
  - Seal Harbor - Churches - Saint Mary's and Saint Jude's Church, 1924-1961 (Box 68, Folder 681)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributions to Episcopal church. Varying relations with Larger Parish as rectors changed. Contributions continued by Martha Baird Rockefeller. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Martha Baird Rockefeller.
  - Seal Harbor - Churches - Saint Mary's and Saint Jude's Church - Misunderstanding, 1950 (Box 68, Folder 682)
    Episcopal parish stops participation in Larger Parish activities.
  - Seal Harbor - Churches - Union Congregational, 1937-1951 (Box 68, Folder 683)
    Incidental gifts by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Bodman Memorial plaque. Building plans. Board of trustees of church. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Robert DeRevere.
  - Seal Harbor - Churches - Union Congregational - By-Laws, 1918-1949 (Box 68, Folder 684)
    Three editions. One major revision in 1949.
  - Seal Harbor - Churches - Union Congregational - Contributions, 1921-1961 (Box 68, Folder 685)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s contributions to Golden Rule Society, $100 annually.
  - Seal Harbor - Churches - Union Congregational - Securities and Investments, 1917-1939 (Box 68, Folder 686)
    Investment of endowment fund of $2,500. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s participation.
  - Seal Harbor - Churches - Union Congregational - Use of Whitmore Building, 1951-1960 (Box 68, Folder 687)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s offer of building for meeting place for organizations. Named Abby Chapel. Dedication.
  - Seal Harbor - Clubs - Cliff Tennis Club, 1915-1927 (Box 68, Folder 688)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. a stockholding member. Club dissolved. Assets distributed to stockholders. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Seal Harbor - Clubs - Harbor Club, 1926-1938 (Box 68, Folder 689)
    Edsel Ford and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. establish club. Provide financing. Company formed to hold club called Bracey Cove Land Company. John D. Rockefeller 3rd represented his father legally but John D. Rockefeller, Jr. remained very interested in club facilities. Membership. Maintenance. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Edsel Ford owned the club, made up annual deficits. In 1942 club closed for war. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. bought out Edsel Ford's interest in 1944. Reopened in 1946 with Nelson A. Rockefeller and David Rockefeller taking responsibility, leasing club from John D. Rockefeller, Jr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. made gifts to club to assist in extraordinary expenditures. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Edsel Ford, Ernest Kanzler, Nelson A. Rockefeller, David Rockefeller, John J. O'Brien.
  - Seal Harbor - Clubs - Harbor Club, 1939-1953 (Box 68, Folder 690)
    David Rockefeller material removed to Folder 690A.
  - Seal Harbor - Clubs - Harbor Club, 1939-1953 (Box 68, Folder 0690A)
  - Seal Harbor - Clubs - Harbor Club, 1953-1960 (Box 69, Folder 691)
    David Rockefeller material removed to Folder 691A.
  - Seal Harbor - Clubs - Harbor Club, 1953-1960 (Box 69, Folder 0691A)
  - Seal Harbor - Clubs - Harbor Club - Deed and Transfer of Property, 1926-1939 (Box 69, Folder 692)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. transfers Swimming Club property to Land Company in preparation for Seal Harbor Club.
  - Seal Harbor - Clubs - Harbor Club - Deed to Nelson A. Rockefeller and David Rockefeller, 1958-1961 (Box 69, Folder 0692A)
    Gift of club to Nelson A. Rockefeller, David Rockefeller as joint tenant.
  - Seal Harbor - Clubs - Harbor Club - Miss Greenwood, 1927-1946 (Box 69, Folder 693)
    Managed club, 1927-1942. Reports to John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Seal Harbor - Clubs - Harbor Club - Inventory and Lease, 1946-1947 (Box 69, Folder 694)
    Documents for 1946 transfer by John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Seal Harbor - Clubs - Harbor Club - Minutes of Meetings, 1927-1942 (Box 69, Folder 695)
  - Seal Harbor - Clubs - Harbor Club - Reorganization Material, 1941-1942 (Box 69, Folder 696)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Edsel Ford decide to drop financing of club. Members try to take over.
  - Seal Harbor - Clubs - Harbor Club - Stockholders Agreement, 1927-1934 (Box 69, Folder 697)
    Basic club agreement. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Edsel Ford principal stockholders.
  - Seal Harbor - Clubs - Harbor Club - Swimming Pool, 1931-1942 (Box 69, Folder 698)
    Heating pool, repairs.
  - Seal Harbor - Clubs - Harbor Club - Bracy Cove Company - Correspondence, 1928-1944 (Box 69, Folder 699)
    Company which owned the land of the Harbor Club. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. owned the company. Sold land to Harbor Club for stock. Bought Edsel Ford's share of stock in Harbor Club carrying land with it from Mrs. Ford in 1944. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Edsel Ford, Thomas M. Debevoise.
  - Seal Harbor - Clubs - Harbor Club - Bracy Cove Company - Capital Stock Tax, 1933-1943 (Box 69, Folder 700)
    Payments of tax.
  - Seal Harbor - Clubs - Harbor Club - Bracy Cove Company - Dissolution, 1945 (Box 69, Folder 701)
    Dissolution of company.
  - Seal Harbor - Clubs - Harbor Club - Closing, 1942 (Box 69, Folder 702)
    Edsel Ford and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. decide to close the club in 1942 for the duration of the war. Corporation dissolved for tax purposes. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Phillip Keebler, Thomas M. Debevoise.
  - Seal Harbor - Clubs - Harbor Club - Cottages, 1956-1960 (Box 69, Folder 0702A)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. finances building of cottages for lease by Harbor Club. Renting of cottages. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., David Rockefeller.
  - Seal Harbor - Clubs - Harbor Club - Cottages - Payments, 1956-1959 (Box 69, Folder 0702B)
    To contractor, architect, estate work.
  - Seal Harbor - Clubs - Harbor Club - Incorporation, 1937-1939 (Box 69, Folder 703)
    Club incorporated in 1937 to separate its affairs from those of the Bracy Cove Company. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Edsel Ford.
  - Seal Harbor - Clubs - Harbor Club - Incorporation - Certificate of Incorporation, 1939 (Box 69, Folder 704)
  - Seal Harbor - Clubs - Harbor Club - Incorporation - Lease from Bracy Cove Land Company, 1939-1942 (Box 69, Folder 705)
  - Seal Harbor - Clubs - Harbor Club - Swimming Pools - Cove Club, 1925-1928 (Box 70, Folder 706)
    Edsel Ford, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., and R. B. Jackson agree to build swimming pool at Seal Harbor. Construction. Purification of water problem. Organization for management of pool. Beginnings of Harbor Club. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Edsel Ford, H. McAlpen, Amy Montague.
  - Seal Harbor - Clubs - Harbor Club - Swimming Pools - Cove Club - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Pledge, 1926 (Box 70, Folder 707)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s pledge toward swimming pool costs. Never paid as Harbor Club developed instead.
  - Seal Harbor - Clubs - Harbor Club - Taxes, 1933-1943 (Box 70, Folder 708)
    State franchise tax, income tax, excise taxes. Club delinquent in taxes on dues. Paid in lump in 1937. Then it was discovered that the club was not liable for taxes because of its structure. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., George Williams.
  - Seal Harbor - Clubs - Harbor Club - Taxes - Claim for Exemption, 1940-1941 (Box 70, Folder 709)
  - Seal Harbor - Clubs - Harbor Club - Tennis Pro, 1937-1947 (Box 70, Folder 710)
    Selection of tennis pro for club in 1937. His employment. Correspondents include John D.Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Seal Harbor - Clubs - Kebo Valley Club, 1926-1959 (Box 70, Folder 711)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. became member of golf club to express his interest in island activities. Loaned club $1,000 in 1935. Loan made gift in 1937. Membership continued until death. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., D. H. Morris, J. J. O'Brien.
  - Seal Harbor - Clubs - Miscellaneous, 1933-1939 (Box 70, Folder 712)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. membership and investments in Maine clubs. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Seal Harbor - Clubs - Men's Club, 1947-1953 (Box 70, Folder 713)
    Small annual gifts by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Nelson A. Rockefeller to Seal Harbor club which provided skating rink, swimming float. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur W. Packard, Nelson A. Rockefeller.
    David Rockefeller material removed to Folder 713A.
  - Seal Harbor - Clubs - Men's Club - David Rockefeller, 1947-1953 (Box 70, Folder 0713A)
    Small annual gifts by David Rockefeller to Seal Harbor club which provided skating rink, swimming float. Correspondents include David Rockefeller.
  - Seal Harbor - Clubs - Yacht Club, 1921-1941 (Box 70, Folder 714)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. a governor of the club. Helped make up year end deficits. Rockefeller boats kept at this club. Special contributions for repairs and upkeep. Nelson A. Rockefeller interested in club. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller, Edward K. Dunham.
    David Rockefeller material removed to Folder 714A.
  - Seal Harbor - Clubs - Yacht Club - David Rockefeller, 1921-1941 (Box 70, Folder 0714A)
    David Rockefeller interested in club. Correspondents include David Rockefeller.
  - Seal Harbor - Clubs - Yacht Club - Stock, 1923-1939 (Box 70, Folder 715)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. purchased stock in club. Given to Nelson A. Rockefeller in 1939.
  - Seal Harbor - Community Hall Association, 1949-1958 (Box 70, Folder 716)
    Successor to Neighborhood Hall Association. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Nelson A. Rockefeller made contributions. Hall rented to research laboratory in 1958. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller.
    David Rockefeller material removed to Folder 716A.
  - Seal Harbor - Community Hall Association - David Rockefeller, 1949-1958 (Box 70, Folder 0716A)
    David Rockefeller made contributions. Correspondents include David Rockefeller.
  - Seal Harbor - Construction - Duncan Candler, 1910-1917 (Box 70, Folder 717)
    Reconstruction of Clarke house. New addition interior and exterior. Candler was architect. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Duncan Candler.
  - Seal Harbor - Construction - Duncan Candler - Commissions, 1911-1920 (Box 70, Folder 718)
    Commissions paid to Candler.
  - Seal Harbor - Construction - Duncan Candler - Yamanaka, 1916-1919 (Box 70, Folder 719)
    Purchase of Japanese screens for dining room.
  - Seal Harbor - Construction - A. E. Clement, 1915-1921 (Box 71, Folder 720)
    Road construction, hauling contractor. Correspondents include A. E. Clement, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Seal Harbor - Construction - A. E. Clement - Mr. Kirk, 1915-1916 (Box 71, Folder 721)
    Architect in Candler's office, information on house work.
  - Seal Harbor - Construction - Hecla Slate Company, 1915-1917 (Box 71, Folder 722)
    Slate roof on Eyrie. Guarantee against leaks.
  - Seal Harbor - Construction - Hecla Slate Company - Old English Slate Company, 1916-1917 (Box 71, Folder 723)
    Manufacturer of slate.
  - Seal Harbor - Construction - Statements, 1915-1916 (Box 71, Folder 724)
    Cost of construction summaries on various houses and buildings at Seal Harbor.
  - Seal Harbor - Clubs - Country Club of Mount Desert, 1910-1930 (Box 71, Folder 725)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Abby Aldrich Rockefeller stockholding members of club. Club liquidation in 1916. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Seal Harbor - Frank E. Davis Stable, 1937-1941 (Box 71, Folder 726)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Mrs. Edward K. Dunham owned stable jointly. Shared expenses. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. sold stable to Mrs. Dunham's heirs. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Edward K. Dunham.
  - Seal Harbor - Deer Problem, 1938-1955 (Box 71, Folder 727)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. concerned over destruction of vegetation in Acadia Park because of the overpopulation of deer. Discussion of problem by naturalists. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s decision to post land if open hunting allowed on island. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Horace M. Albright, Lawrie Holmes, Newton B. Drury.
  - Seal Harbor - Robert F. DeRevere, 1931-1960 (Box 71, Folder 728)
    Became superintendent in 1931. Transfer of funds, office houses, employees. Health, vacations, etc. Succeeded S. F. Ralston as superintendent of Seal Harbor estate. General care of estate. Home for DeRevere. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Robert F. DeRevere, Frank S. Staley, Robert W. Gumbel.
  - Seal Harbor - Robert F. DeRevere, 1931-1960 (Box 71, Folder 0728A)
  - Seal Harbor - Robert F. DeRevere - Gift of Land and Money, 1948-1953 (Box 71, Folder 729)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. assists DeRevere in building home.
  - Seal Harbor - Robert F. DeRevere - Budget, 1956-1960 (Box 71, Folder 730)
  - Seal Harbor - Donations, 1912-1935 (Box 71, Folder 731)
    Small Rockefeller gifts to local causes. Effect of summer people on Maine community. Gifts to causes and individuals. Boy Scouts, individuals, general policy on giving small scattered gifts for special projects. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Seal Harbor - Donations, 1938-1959 (Box 71, Folder 732)
  - Seal Harbor - Donations - Lists of Maine Donations, 1936-1959 (Box 72, Folder 733)
  - Seal Harbor - Donations - Pledge to Mrs. Charles P. Simpson, 1928-1938 (Box 72, Folder 734)
    Widow of Seal Harbor friend received $1,000 a year.
  - Seal Harbor - Eyrie, 1947-1960 (Box 72, Folder 735)
    Repairs and alterations to house. Requests from strangers to visit Eyrie. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Janet Warfield.
  - Seal Harbor - Eyrie - Bathroom Alterations, 1954 (Box 72, Folder 736)
    Changes made for Martha Baird Rockefeller.
  - Seal Harbor - Eyrie - Elevator, 1938-1957 (Box 72, Folder 737)
    Installation, repairs, modernization.
  - Seal Harbor - Mrs. Beatrix Farrand, 1928-1941, 1968 (Box 72, Folder 738)
    Landscape gardener. Cooperated with John D. Rockefeller, Jr. in planning work in various sections of the island. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s concern over appearance of road sides and bridges. Mrs. Farrand made no charges for her services in connection with the road work for several years. Correspondents include Beatrix Farrand, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Seal Harbor - Fire Department, 1927-1961 (Box 72, Folder 739)
    Purchase of tickets to firemen's ball annually. 1949 contribution to fire equipment purchase. 1954 contribution toward jeep. Nelson A. Rockefeller made annual contributions. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller, Martha Baird Rockefeller.
    David Rockefeller material removed to Folder 739A.
  - Seal Harbor - Fire Department, 1927-1961 (Box 72, Folder 0739A)
    David Rockefeller made annual contributions. Correspondents include David Rockefeller.
  - Seal Harbor - Fire Protection, 1930-1959 (Box 72, Folder 740)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contribution toward Seal Harbor fire engine. Internal protection in Eyrie's insurance rates. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Robert W. Gumbel, Robert F. DeRevere.
  - Seal Harbor - Forestry and Planting - Thomas Patten and Louisa Patten, 1921-1927 (Box 72, Folder 741)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. employed Thomas Patten for outside work. After his death, John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave small gifts to his widow.
  - Seal Harbor - Furniture and Furnishings, 1948-1953 (Box 72, Folder 742)
    Fabrics, outdoor furniture. Correspondents include Robert W. Gumbel.
  - Seal Harbor - Furnishings - Lists, 1911-1916 (Box 72, Folder 743)
    Inventory of furniture, 1916. Lists.
  - Seal Harbor - Furnishings - Hampton Shops, 1915-1917 (Box 72, Folder 744)
    Purchase of bedroom furniture.
  - Seal Harbor - Furnishings - A. Sperling, 1916 (Box 72, Folder 745)
    Purchased tables and chairs from Sperling.
  - Seal Harbor - Furnishings - Arnold Talbot, 1917 (Box 72, Folder 746)
    Purchased small rugs.
  - Seal Harbor - Furnishings - Whittridge and Barrows, 1916-1918 (Box 72, Folder 747)
    Purchased awnings and curtains here.
  - Seal Harbor - Garage, 1915-1926 (Box 72, Folder 748)
    Construction. Later reconstruction of parking garage. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Duncan Candler, Charles O. Heydt.
  - Seal Harbor - Garden at Eyrie, 1926-1939 (Box 73, Folder 749)
    Garden built especially around Korean figures. Beatrix Farrand supervised the work. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. kept close watch. Soil brought in, seeded each year. Changes in garden. This is the Chinese or Oriental Garden. Water supply. Visitors. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s intense careful interest in the garden. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Beatrix Farrand, Abby Aldrich Rockefeller.
  - Seal Harbor - Garden at Eyrie, 1946-1949 (Box 73, Folder 750)
  - Seal Harbor - Garden at Eyrie, 1950-1961, 1984 (Box 73, Folder 751)
  - Seal Harbor - Garden at Eyrie - Chinese Tile, 1928-1930 (Box 73, Folder 752)
  - Seal Harbor - Garden at Eyrie - University of California, Berkeley Files, 1932-1934, 1984 (Box 73, Folder 753)
  - Seal Harbor - Garden at Eyrie - Amemya Photographs, 1934-1949 (Box 73, Folder 754)
    Nelson A. Rockefeller has photos made of Gardens.
  - Seal Harbor - Gate Houses - Jordan Pond and Brown Mountain, 1931-1941 (Box 73, Folder 755)
    Built by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. to match architecture of Acadia Park. Atterbury designed them and supervised the construction. Built by Smallidge. Occupancy of gate houses. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s pleasure in this architecture. Correspondents include Grosvenor Atterbury, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Paul D. Simpson.
  - Seal Harbor - Hancock County Trustees of Public Reservations, 1925-1951 (Box 73, Folder 756)
    Organization created nucleus of Acadia National Park. Formed in 1901. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. worked through it in early years. Short history of organization. Contribution to memorial for George B. Dorr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. felt it should disband when national park was realized. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Seal Harbor - Hancock County Trustees of Public Reservations - Champlain Monument, 1940-1948 (Box 73, Folder 757)
    Relocated on land given to town by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. in exchange for old site.
  - Seal Harbor - Incinerator, 1927-1931 (Box 73, Folder 758)
    Garbage disposal problem. Suggested use of sea urged by villages. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. interested because of view and roads. He contributed toward project. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., George Dorr.
  - Seal Harbor - Kindergarten Association, 1921-1946 (Box 74, Folder 759)
    Contributions to summer time kindergarten for town children. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller.
  - Seal Harbor - Lafayette National Park Museum, 1927-1950 (Box 74, Folder 760)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributes $15,000 toward Museum on area's early pre-history. Museum transferred to government as part of Acadia National Park. Later requests denied. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Robert Abbe.
  - Seal Harbor - Lafayette National Park Museum - History of Mount Desert, 1880-1960 (Box 74, Folder 761)
    Clippings and booklets collected by John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Seal Harbor - Library, 1916-1961 (Box 74, Folder 762)